Schneider, Anna Weinstock Papers 5143
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Anna Weinstock Schneider Papers
1921-1967
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Weinstock Schneider, Anna
5143
1.5 cubic feet
1.5 linear ft.
Papers (documents), correspondence, transcripts, interviews.
Writings by, correspondence with, and recording and transcript of interview with Anna Weinstock Schneider.
5555843
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
C. Eastman, September 27, 2005
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, November 01, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Schneider was the first woman Commissioner of Conciliation, U.S. Department of Labor appointed in 1922. A member of several minimum wage boards in Massachusetts, lobbyist for labor legislation in Massachusetts and organizer for the Massachusetts Suffrage Association, she was also active in union activities as President of Boston Women's Trade Union League and organizer for the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
Scope and Contents
Writings by, correspondence with, and recording and transcript of interview with Anna Weinstock Schneider.
The collection is arranged in five series: biographical data, correspondence, manuscripts, miscellany, and oral history interview.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5143 AV: Anna Weinstock Schneider Audio Tapes 5143 mf: Anna Weinstock Schneider Papers on Microfilm
Arrangement
Series I: Biographical Data
Series II: Correspondence
Series III: Manuscripts
Series IV: Miscellany
Series V: Oral History Interview
Schnieder, Anna W. (Anna Weinstock)
5555843
- Series I: Biographical Data
  - Periodical articles about Anna Weinstock Schnieder, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    July-Sept.
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Correspondence to and from Anna Weinstock Schnieder, 1921-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes thank you letters, congratulation letters on 35 years service, etc.
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    August 13-Dec. 16; Recommendations of Anna Weinstock for position of labor mediator made mainly to James J. Davis and Henry Cabot Lodge. Also general appointment to Commissioner of Conciliation.
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    March 24-Feb.23; To and from Frank Brown, Regional Director, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    June 2-3; To Mr. Howard T. Colvin, Regional Director, Bureau of Conciliation, U.S. Department of Labor
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1922-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Nov. 29-Aug 7; To Honorable James Davis, Secretary of U.S. Department of Labor from various sources
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    March 24; To Joseph F. Finnegan, Director, Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1948-1950 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    July 1-Oct. 30; To and from Daniel F. Hurley Regional Director, U.S. Mediation and Conciliation Service
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1925-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Aug. 26-July 11; To and from H.L. Kerwin, Director of Conciliation, U.S. Department of Labor
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Aug. 9; To Edward McGrady, Assistant Secretary of Labor, U.S. Department of Labor
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1940-1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    May 10-Feb. 6; To and from Frances Perkins, Secretary of Labor, U.S. Department of Labor
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    March 27-March 30; To William E. Simkin, Director of Federal Mediation and Conciliation Services
  - Correspondence RE: Anna Weinstock, 1938-1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Aug. 11-Dec. 7; To Dr. J.R. Steelman, Director of Conciliation, U.S. Department of Labor
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1924-1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    May 5, 1924 partment of Conciliation, U.S. Department; November 25, of Labor re: Anna Weinstock Schnieder; 1933 Commissioner of Conciliation
- Series III: Manuscripts
  - Typed and handwritten transcript by Anna Weinstock Schnieder (Box 1, Folder 15)
    36 pgs
- Series IV: Miscellany
  - Programs (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Invitations, Announcements and Christmas cards (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper clippings about Anna Weinstock Schnieder (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper clippings about Anna Weinstock Schnieder (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper clippings about Anna Weinstock Schnieder (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper clippings about Anna Weinstock Schnieder (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Newspaper clippings about Anna Weinstock Schnieder (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Newspaper clippings on textile mill strike in Elizabethton, Tenn., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series V: Oral History Interview
  - Oral History Interview with Anna Weinstock Schnieder transcript (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Pt. 1
  - Oral History Interview with Anna Weinstock Schnieder transcript (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Pt. 2
  - Oral History Interview with Anna Weinstock Schnieder carbon copy (Box 4, Folder 1)